Now, let's see, of all this in action, I will show you how to inspect HTTP traffic using your browser built in developer stores.
So, opening dev tools, you need to just, if you are in Windows or Linux, just press F2, F2L, or you can press Ctrl+Shift+I, and in your browser,
you can do also, like, right click upon your web browser, and you can see that inspect tab,
and just, you can see the network, right?
Now, basically, what does it mean this network tab? Basically, it means, like, this is where all HTTP magic happens.
The network tab shows you, shows you every single request your browser makes. Let me work you through what we will see.
Demo one, viewer simple get request, just, just, okay, just, let's take an example.
Let's go to this, yeah, let's go to this flip card, okay, and let's re-open it, okay, let's re-open it, inspect network tab, and write that search button, yeah.
So, we want, we want, like, shows, okay, see, when I just query it for shows, see, shows, right?
So, here you can see, watch the request, you can see, this is the get request, right?
And there are a lot of, a lot of things, a lot of, what you will see, like, all HTML source, all HTML pages with the status board. Let me show you this, very perfectly, yeah.
Yeah, now you will able to see that, that HTML page, and this CSS page, this PNG, JAs, right, and there are a lot of things, a lot of stuffs over here.
So, basically, now let's see the header tab, here you can see the header tab, yeah, see, this is, this request URL, see, this is the request URL, right?
See, this is the request URL, what was the request method, the get is the request method, what was the status board, 200, okay, okay.
So, request header, request header, what browser sent and a response header, what server sent back, okay. So, this is the request header, and this is the response header, see.
Let me show you the status board, you can see, this is the request header, this is the internal header, which is already talked about host header, right?
User regency, this is my device information and browser information, right, and let's see, here you can see this is the response header, okay.
So, basically, the response tab at the actual HTML, CSS, JAs, content received, okay, and preview the tab, okay, format it view of the responses, you can see, right.
Now, let me show you a view from submission post request, let's add to cart, and let's again go to back, and here you can see add to cart, right.
Now, inspect, now network, now just zero, okay, it's not worked, okay, let's remove, remove, and this was removed successfully, right.
But I was not able to get that delete, that delete request, see.
So basically, let's submit a form, feedback, feedback form, online, let's take it.
Nope, don't, I won't like.
Okay, let me, let me show you the login.
Now, let's take this mail over here, and let's put it over here, and it was sort of me.
Okay, it says that interview phone number, no, so on, no, I can't share the phone number, okay.
So, let's take it, test PHP, okay, so our guest, our guest book, let's open the inspector, go to the network tab, now let's do something like,
guest book, and put the guest book, add message, and here you can see, this message was sent by post method, right.
Now, let's check the login forms, okay, login forms like, let's say Panasonic, okay, Panasonic, and these are the login forms.
Now, let's open the inspect, network, and put, add mean admin, and login, see.
See the request made in post method, right.
See username, admin, password, admin, right.
So this request made in post method.
So this is how post method works, okay.
Now, let's understand, let's understand the inspect, inspecting cookies, okay, inspecting cookies, so, let's check it out, yeah, this one.
So, how to inspect the cookies, you can see inspect, go to the application tab, you can see the application tab.
Now, click on cookies, you can see, this is the cookies, right, which was working inside of this, like URL, right.
Now, filtering request, the network tab can get overhaul with 100 of request.
So, let me, let me show you how you can filter the request, okay.
So, I want, sorry, I want only, like, only like fetch XHR, like this one, okay.
So, what I need to do, I need to just tap over here and see, let's, let's see.
It's not working, right.
Now, let's check document, talk, you can see there is a document format, you see.
So, this is the filtering machine technique, so I want CSS, see the all CSS files.
Now, I want JSON files, see, you can see the all JSON files, which were working over here.
Now, I want font, you can see the fonts.
And now, I want see the image, you can see the image, media, okay, no, no, there are no media files over here.
No, a manifest files, no, shock it files, no custom files, right.
You can see the, if I will tap over here, all, I will see the all request, which was made.
By me, to this Panasonic server, okay.
So, this is how this filtration will work.
Now, let's understand, like, checking status code.
I will intentionally trigger different status code, okay.
So, let's go to this, yeah, inspect, network, now see, four or three.
So, what does it mean, four or three forbidden, okay, because of why forbidden?
Because of I, I just did any kind of malforms, things, or malforms, like, like, I just send some kind of malform payloads.
For that reason, their firewall blocks me, okay.
But this was for me already, okay.
So, now, let's talk about four or four.
Now, let's check it over here.
Now, put admin admin.
Let's try it over here.
See, what it says, four or four, not found.
Why?
The source is not available, or try to load a page that doesn't exist, right.
So, for that reason, I'm getting four or four.
Now, let's see the, I have already told you about 301, 401.
Now, analyze load times, performance matters, I will show you, okay.
So, how can we see that performance?
So, okay, debug, okay.
So, in the network tab, okay.
So, what we need to do, performance matter, I will show you.
So, the first thing, which one is waterfall view, visual timeline of when each request
happened, see which request starts loop, identify portal links, and timing tabs, DNS
lookup, how long to find the server, connecting to established connection, waiting TTFD,
which is time to first byte, okay.
And we need to see that content download, okay.
So, basically the time to download response, okay.
So, let's open it.
Let's check it out, try this after this session, open any website like Amazon, Amazon.com,
open directive tools, network tab, and then refresh the page, and find the first request,
usually that the HTML document within an HTML document, and click on it and explore
what status word did it return, and what HTTP method was used, and what cookies were sent,
how long did it take to load.
So, here you can see the time to take load about 6, 1, 5 milliseconds of this application.
Now, let's see the Google.
How many time it takes to load?
I am able to see, so this is the time to take to load, okay.
Thank you guys.